wpspublish.com 2016-11-06

# WPS | unlocking potential > Home > Privacy Statement

At WPS, your privacy is very important to us. PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING CAREFULLY. If you are under the age of eighteen (18), please read with your parent or guardian.

Because WPS respects your privacy, we do not sell, rent, trade, or share with any other organization, the personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you supply us. As part of our business operation, we gather certain types Personal Information from users of our website and for various WPS activities, operations, and business purposes. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, disclose, manage, and store the Personal Information that you may provide to us. This Privacy Policy is a part of WPS’ Terms of Use, which is binding on all website users. 

If you do not agree with our Privacy Policy, please do not participate in WPS's online or off-line activities or services that require you to provide your Personal Information. 

### Website collection, use, and disclosure of personal information

WPS recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of visitors to our website. As you interact with our website, we may collect certain types of Personal Information about you. We consider the following to be Personal Information: your name, street address, phone number, credit card information, and e-mail address. Personal Information is used by WPS to process your online purchases, to inform you about our products and services, to improve the products and services we offer, and otherwise to better meet the needs and preferences of WPS customers. We do not share your Personal Information with any unaffiliated third parties. We may share this information with our operational service providers, the specialists that provide internal support to WPS's operations including maintenance, management, storage, disposal of Personal Information, and/or fulfillment of services and your online purchases. If any operational services providers are provided access to your Personal Information, they are required to protect it in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy (for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for us). 

We also may disclose your Personal Information to comply with court orders or subpoenas or when required to do so by law. We may also disclose such data in cooperation with a law enforcement or government request or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use Agreement, or to comply with legal or regulatory obligations. In addition, we may transfer information to a third party in the event of corporate restructuring (e.g., a sale, merger or other transfer of assets). 

WPS reserves the right to monitor your use of the website to determine if you are complying with our terms, and the right, in its sole discretion, to terminate your access to the website.

### California Privacy Rights

Residents of the State of California, under a provision of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. WPS does not disclose Personal Information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. 

### Cookies

To enhance your experience with our website, some of our web pages may use "cookies." Cookies are small data files that are sent to your browser or related software from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies track where you travel on our website and what you look at and purchase. All of these purposes serve to improve and personalize your experience on our website. This website also uses cookies to facilitate the checkout process. If you choose to change your browser preferences to disable cookies, you will still be able to make a purchase at WPS. However, you will have to re-enter your purchasing information each time you return to the store to make a purchase. 

Most web browsers can be set to inform you when a cookie has been sent to you and provide you with the opportunity to refuse that cookie. However, refusing a cookie may, in some cases, preclude you from using, or negatively impact the display or function of, the website or certain areas or features of the website. 

### IP Address 

Our server automatically collects data about your server's Internet address when you visit us. This information, known as an Internet Protocol address, or IP Address, is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider whenever you're on the Internet. When you request pages from our website, our servers may log your IP Address and sometimes your domain name. Our server may also record the referring page that linked you to us (e.g., another web site or a search engine); the pages you visit on this website; the website you visit after this website; the ads you see and/or click on; other information about the type of web browser, computer, platform, related software, and settings you are using; any search terms you have entered on this website or a referral site; and other web usage activity and data logged by our web servers. We use this information for internal system administration, to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Such information may also be used to gather broad demographic information, such as country of origin and Internet service provider. We may also link this information with your Personal Information.

### Links to Third Party Websites

This website may provide links to other third party websites or resources. Such links to third party websites on this site are provided solely as a convenience to you, and do not constitute or imply an endorsement, sponsorship or recommendation of, or affiliation with the third party or its products and services. WPS has not reviewed all of these third party sites and does not control and is not responsible for any of these sites or their content. Thus, WPS makes no representations whatsoever about any other website, which you may access through this website, or any information, software, or other products or materials, found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked from this site, you acknowledge and agree that WPS is not responsible for the availability of such external sites or resources and is not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, products, services, or other materials on or available from such sites or resources. It is up to you to take precautions to ensure that whatever you select for your use is free of such items as viruses, worms, Trojan horses, and other items of a destructive nature, and you do so entirely at your own risk. Accordingly, you agree that WPS shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such third-party materials, content, products or services available on or through any such site or resource.

### Pixel Tags

We may use pixel tags (aka "web beacons" or "clear GIFs") or similar technologies on the website and/or in our communications with you to enable us to know whether you have visited a web page or received a message. This is typically a one-pixel, transparent image (although it can be a visible image as well), located on a web page or in an e-mail or other type of message, which is retrieved from a remote site on the Internet enabling the verification of an individual's viewing or receipt of a web page or message. This may enable us to relate your viewing or receipt of a web page or message to other information about you, including your Personal Information. 

### Security of Personal Information

In connection with your purchases at wpspublish.com, we may use a third party operational service provider to collect your credit card number. The third party operational service provider conducts the financial transaction in a secured manner by collecting your payment information through a secured Internet connection via SSL. The third party payment mechanism will be accessible via a hyperlink from the website and the third party operational service provider will be solely responsible for all financial transactions and the collection, use, and storage of your credit card [or debit card] information. In connection with your purchases, the website may request additional Personal Information such as full name, billing and shipping address, e-mail address and telephone number, and any such information that is required to fulfill your order and to communicate with you regarding your order. We will only use your credit card number to complete the specific transaction you requested. 

Please remember that no data transmission over the Internet, or by other means, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Thus, while we strive to protect your personal data, WPS cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. As noted above, our third party operational service provider uses a secured connection for the collection of payment information, but we do not use a secured connection for other types of activities. Therefore, you understand, acknowledge, and agree that you transmit certain Personal Information over this website at your own risk. 

Once we receive your data, we use reasonable efforts to ensure the information you provide is secure and not readily available to unauthorized individuals or third parties. 

### Children's Privacy

Children should not provide any Personal Information without permission from their parent, guardian, or teacher. WPS follows the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We do not condition children's participation in an online activity on the disclosure of more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity. We do not share children's information with outside third parties not bound by this Privacy Policy, or otherwise inconsistent with the requirements of COPPA. If you are a parent or legal guardian and would like to review any Personal Information that we have collected online from your child, have this information deleted, and/or request that there be no further collection or use of your child's information or if you have questions about these information practices, you may contact us at: 

WPS - Western Psychological Services  
625 Alaska Avenue  
Torrance, CA 90503-5124

or via email: [privacy@wpspublish.com](mailto:privacy@wpspublish.com)

### WPS Advertising and Promotional Emails

WPS only sends advertising and promotional e-mails to those who have opted to receive such communications. You can "opt-out" of receiving advertising and promotional e-mail from us in compliance with federal law by following the opt-out instructions in our e-mail messages. To ensure that your opt-out request is honored, you must use the designated method in the e-mail message to notify us of your opt-out request, as we cannot guarantee that other methods of notification will be effective or timely. Please note that even if you choose to opt-out of WPS's marketing, we will continue to send you important service-related communications (e.g., order confirmations). 

### Monitoring and Use of Aggregate Information

We reserve the right to monitor and edit any Personal Information about our users, including information about the use of website activities and services and the contents of users' e-mail messages for internal purposes. We will take such measures if we believe it is necessary to protect the security, integrity, and operations of this website or WPS. We may disclose aggregate statistics regarding our users and user behavior as a measure of interest in and use of our website, such as overall patterns or demographic reports that do not describe or identify any individual user. 

### Changes to our Policy

We may revise this policy at any time by updating this posting without advance notice to you. Such revisions shall be effective to you immediately upon posting. Therefore, we encourage you to visit our website to review this Privacy Policy often. 

### Contact Information

If you have questions or comments about our privacy policy or our practices, you may contact us by e-mail at [privacy@wpspublish.com](mailto:privacy@wpspublish.com)or via mail at:

WPS - Western Psychological Services  
625 Alaska Avenue  
Torrance, CA 90503-5124

**Privacy Policy last updated September 26, 2012**
